<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<filmographie>


    <film filmref="f62" realisateur="Gunnar Skoglund" date="1932" misc="(uncredited)" personnage="Girl waiting in line">
        <titre>Landskamp</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f58" realisateur="Gustav Edgren" date="1935" personnage="Lena Bergström">
        <titre>Valborgsmässoafton</titre>
        <resume>Lena Bergstroem works in an office and is unhappily in love with her boss, Johan Borg. She decides to
            quit. Borg's wife won't have any children, and when she becomes pregnant she has an illegal abortion. For
            some reason, Lena's father believes that it is Lena who has had an abortion.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1935" pays="USA">Walpurgis Night</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f59" img="59.jpg" pdf="59.pdf" realisateur="Gustav Molander" date="1935" personnage="Astrid">
        <titre>Swedenhielms</titre>
        <resume>The Swedenhielm's is an old aristocratic family. The head of the family is professor Rolf Swedenhielm.
            His three children Bo, Julia and Rolf jr also live in the house. They also have an excellent house maid,
            Boman. Because of the family's extravagance, they are heading for bankruptcy. But perhaps their problems
            would be solved if Rolf was awarded the Nobel Prize?
        </resume>
        <alias date="1935" pays="USA">Swedenhielms Family</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f60" realisateur="Ivar Johansson" date="1935" personnage="Karin Ingman">
        <titre>Bränningar</titre>
        <resume>Daniel has been forced by his father to become a priest. After graduating, he comes to a parish in
            Haelsingland. During one stormy night, he seduces a young girl, Karin, and rapes her. Filled with regret, he
            runs out into the dark night and is struck by lightning. He loses his memory and is taken to a distant
            hospital to recover. Meanwhile Karin gets pregnant and has a child. Eventually Daniel comes back and when he
            meets Karin his memory returns.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1935">Ocean Breakers</alias>
        <alias date="1949" pays="USA">Surf, The</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f61" img="61.jpg" pdf="61.pdf" realisateur="Edvin Adolphson" date="1935" personnage="Elsa Edlund">
        <titre>Munkbrogreven</titre>
        <resume>In one of the narrow streets of the Old town of Stockholm lies hotel City. It's filled by mysterious
            characters such as 'Greven', 'Blomman' and others. The police inspector Goeransson is chasing a jewel thief,
            'Diamant-Lasse'.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1935">Count of the Old Monk's Bridge, The</alias>
        <alias date="1935">Count of the Old Town, The</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f56" img="56.jpg" pdf="56.pdf" realisateur="Gustav Molander" date="1936" personnage="Anita Hoffman">
        <titre>Intermezzo</titre>
        <resume>The world famous violinist Holger Brandt comes back to his family after a tour. He and his wife have
            been married for many years, but their love has faded. Their young daughter gets a new piano teacher, Anita
            Hoffman. Mr. Brandt fall in love with her and together they go on a world tour. But he soon discovers that
            the feelings for his wife that he thought were dead return.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1936">Interlude</alias>
        <alias date="1936" pays="USA">Intermezzo</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f57" realisateur="Gustav Molander" date="1936" personnage="Eva Bergh">
        <titre>På solsidan</titre>
        <resume>Eva Bergh works as a bank clerk, but dreams of becoming an artist. At a party she meets the rich Harald
            Ribe and he instantly falls in love with her. When he proposes to marry her she has no work or place to live
            and she accepts. At Harald's estate she can live comfortably, but she misses her old friends.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1936">On the Sunny Side</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f53" img="53.jpg" pdf="53.pdf" realisateur="Gustav Molander" date="1938"
          personnage="Anna Holm/Miss Paulsson">
        <titre>Kvinnas ansikte, En</titre>
        <resume>When she was a child, Anna Holm, burned her face. This destroyed her looks, and she has become a mean
            and bitter woman. She and her 'friends' are black-mailers. One of the victims pay her by letting a plastic
            surgeon, doctor Wegert, make her beautiful again. Anna becomes a new person and leaves the others. She
            becomes a governess for a young boy, who will inherit a fortune. The boy has an evil uncle, who wants to see
            the boy dead, so that he will inherit the fortune. He hires Anna's former colleagues as assassins.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1939" pays="UK">Woman's Face, A</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f54" realisateur="Carl Frölich" date="1938" personnage="Marianne">
        <titre>Vier Gesellen, Die</titre>
        <resume/>
        <alias date="1938">Four Companions, The</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f55" realisateur="Gustav Molander" date="1938" personnage="Julia Balzar">
        <titre>Dollar</titre>
        <resume>Ludvig and Sussi Battwyhl, Louis and Katja Brenner and Julia and Kurt Balzar are upper class
            millionaires. They don't seem to do any real work but still need a vacation in the mountains. Everybody
            seems to be romantically involved with everybody. A rich American woman joins them.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f51" img="51.jpg" pdf="51.pdf" realisateur="Gregory Ratoff" date="1939" personnage="Anita Hoffman">
        <titre>Intermezzo (remake)</titre>
        <resume>A concert violinist becomes charmed with his daughter's talented piano teacher. When he invites her to
            go on tour with him, they make beautiful music away from the concert hall as well. He soon leaves his wife
            so the two can go off to Italy together.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1939" pays="UK">Escape to Happiness</alias>
        <alias date="1939" pays="USA: promotional title">Intermezzo: A Love Story</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f52" img="52.jpg" pdf="52.pdf" realisateur="Gustav Molander" date="1939" personnage="Eva Beckman">
        <titre>En enda natt</titre>
        <resume>Funfair worker Valdemar is without his knowledge the illegitimate son of a rich landowner, colonel von
            Brede. The colonel knows and employs Valdemar as his stable master. The colonel has a young and beautiful
            ward, Eva, but will she and Valdemar fall in love with each other?
        </resume>
        <alias date="1939">One Single Night</alias>
        <alias date="1939">Only One Night</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f50" img="50.jpg" pdf="50.pdf" realisateur="Per Lindberg" date="1940"
          personnage="Kerstin Norbäck/Sara Nordanå">
        <titre>Juninatten</titre>
        <resume>Young Karin Nordbäck lives in a small town. She has a relationship with a sailor, but when she tries to
            leave him, he shoots her. She survives and begins a new life in Stockholm. There she meets kind people and
            new friends but the newspapers find her and start to write about her.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1940">June Night</alias>
        <alias date="1940">Night in June, A</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f47" img="47.jpg" pdf="47.pdf" realisateur="Gregory Ratoff" date="1941" personnage="Emilie Gallatin">
        <titre>Adam Had Four Sons</titre>
        <resume>Emilie has been hired to care for the four sons of wealthy Adam Stoppard and his wife, Molly. After
            Molly dies, Adam and the boys grow to depend on Emilie even more. At the same time, Emilie falls in love
            with Adam. The boys grow up, but Adam insists that Emilie stay on as part of the family. Her relationships
            with both the boys and Adam become strained after one son marries a gold-digging viper named Hester.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1941" pays="USA">Legacy</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f48" img="48.jpg" pdf="48.pdf" realisateur="Victor Fleming" date="1941" personnage="Ivy Peterson">
        <titre>Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde</titre>
        <resume>Dr. Jekyll believes good and evil exist in everyone. Experiments reveal his evil side, named Hyde.
            Experience teaches him how evil Hyde can be: he kills Ivy who earlier expressed interest in Jekyll and Sir
            Charles, Jekyll's faincee's father.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f49" realisateur="W.S. Van Dyke" date="1941" personnage="Stella Bergen">
        <titre>Rage in Heaven</titre>
        <resume>Old friends Ward and Phillip both become smitten with Phillip's mother's attractive young secretary
            Stella. But Stella marries Phillip and stands by him as his behavior becomes more and more erratic and his
            jealousy of Ward increases.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f46" img="46.jpg" pdf="46.pdf" realisateur="Michael Curtiz" date="1942"
          personnage="Ilsa Lund Laszlo">
        <titre>Casablanca</titre>
        <resume>In World War II Casablanca, Rick Blaine, exiled American and former freedom fighter, runs the most
            popular nightspot in town. The cynical lone wolf Blaine comes into the possession of two valuable letters of
            transit. When Nazi Major Strasser arrives in Casablanca, the sycophantic police Captain Renault does what he
            can to please him, including detaining Czech underground leader Victor Laszlo. Much to Rick's surprise,
            Lazslo arrives with Ilsa, Rick's one time love. Rick is very bitter towards Ilsa, who ran out on him in
            Paris, but when he learns she had good reason to, they plan to run off together again using the letters of
            transit. Well, that was their original plan...
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f44" realisateur="?" date="1943" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Swedes in America</titre>
        <resume>[Documentaire]</resume>
        <alias date="1943" pays="UK">Ingrid Bergman Answers</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f45" img="45.jpg" pdf="45.pdf" realisateur="Sam Wood" date="1943" personnage="María">
        <titre>For Whom the Bell Tolls</titre>
        <resume>Spain in the 1930s is the place to be for a man of action like Robert Jordan. There is a civil war going
            on and Jordan who has joined up on the side that appeals most to idealists of that era --- like Ernest
            Hemingway and his friends --- has been given a high-risk assignment up in the mountains. He awaits the right
            time to blow up a bridge in a cave. Pilar, who is in charge there, has an ability to foretell the future.
            And so that night she encourages Maria, a young girl ravaged by enemy soldiers, to join Jordan who has
            decided to spend the night under the stars.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f43" img="43.jpg" pdf="43.pdf" realisateur="George Cukor" date="1944" personnage="Paula Alquist">
        <titre>Gaslight</titre>
        <resume>Paula's aunt Alice Alquist, a famous entertainer, is murdered in her home. Paula, who lives with her
            aunt finds the body. Police fail to find the killer and Paula is sent away to school. Ten years later, Paula
            returns to London with her new husband. They take up residence in her aunt's house, which she has inherited.
            Paula is increasingly isolated by her husband but does come to the attention of an admirerer of her aunt,
            Mr. Brian Cameron.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1944" pays="UK">Murder in Thornton Square</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f40" img="40.jpg" pdf="40.pdf" realisateur="Sam Wood" date="1945" personnage="Clio Dulaine">
        <titre>Saratoga Trunk</titre>
        <resume>On the death of her mother, the vivacious Clio Dulaine returns from Paris to her childhood home in New
            Orleans to seek revenge for the humiliation her mother suffered there from her father's wife's family. She
            also plans to marry a rich man to attain the status and respectability her mother never had, but falls for
            Texas gambler Clint Maroon instead. When he leaves New Orleans for the horse racing season at Saratoga
            Springs, she follows him there to seek her fortune --- or someone else's.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f41" img="41.jpg" pdf="41.pdf" realisateur="Leo McCarey" date="1945" personnage="Sister Benedict">
        <titre>Bells of St. Mary's, The</titre>
        <resume>Father O'Malley the unconventional priest from 'Going My Way' continues his work for the Catholic
            Church. This time he is sent to St. Mary's, a run-down parochial school on the verge of condemnation. He and
            Sister Benedict work together in an attempt to save the school, though their differing methods often lead to
            good-natured disagreements.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f42" img="42.jpg" pdf="42.pdf" realisateur="Alfred Hitchcock" date="1945"
          personnage="Dr. Constance Peterson">
        <titre>Spellbound</titre>
        <resume>The head of the Green Manors mental asylum Dr. Murchison is retiring to be replaced by Dr. Edwards, a
            famous psychiatrist. Edwards arrives and is immediately attracted to the beautiful but cold Dr. Constance
            Petersen. However, it soon becomes apparent that Dr. Edwards is in fact a paranoid amnesiac imposter. He
            goes on the run with Constance who tries to help his condition and solve the mystery of what happened to the
            real Dr. Edwards.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1945" pays="USA: promotional title">Alfred Hitchcock's Spellbound</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f39" img="39.jpg" pdf="39.pdf" realisateur="Alfred Hitchcock" date="1946"
          personnage="Alicia Huberman">
        <titre>Notorious</titre>
        <resume>Alicia Huberman is a frivolous girl who loves drinks and men; her father was a German spy in USA and he
            has committed suicide in prison. Government agent Devlin asks the girl to spy on a group of her father's
            Nazi friends in Rio de Janeiro; this could be her chance to clean her guilty name. The girl falls in love
            with the agent, but he seems not to be attracted by the life she is living. Alicia accepts the duty and she
            goes to Brazil with Devlin. The agent suggests Alicia should marry the spy and gain free access into his
            house, so she does. During a party, Alicia and Devlin find some uranium dust hidden in Sebastian's canteen,
            but now he has discovered Alicia is a spy and he starts poisoning her day after day.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1946">Alfred Hitchcock's Notorious</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f37" img="37.jpg" pdf="37.pdf" realisateur="Victor Fleming" date="1948" personnage="Joan">
        <titre>Joan of Arc</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f38" img="38.jpg" pdf="38.pdf" realisateur="Lewis Milestone" date="1948" personnage="Joan Madou">
        <titre>Arch of Triumph</titre>
        <resume>In winter of 1938, Paris is crowded with refugees from the Nazis, who live in the black shadows of
            night, trying to evade deportation. One such is Dr. Ravic, who practices medicine illegally and stalks his
            old Nazi enemy Haake with murder in mind. One rainy night, Ravic meets Joan Madou, a kept woman cast adrift
            by her lover's sudden death. Against Ravic's better judgement, they become involved in a doomed affair;
            matters come to a crisis on the day war is declared.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f35" img="35.jpg" pdf="35.pdf" realisateur="Roberto Rossellini" date="1949" personnage="Karin">
        <titre>Stromboli</titre>
        <resume>Karen, a young woman from the baltic countries, marries fisherman Antonio to escape from a prisoners
            camp. But the life in Antonio's village, Stromboli, threatened by the vulcano, is a tough one and Karen can
            not get used to it.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1949" pays="Italy">Stromboli, terra di Dio</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f36" img="36.jpg" pdf="36.pdf" realisateur="Alfred Hitchcock" date="1949"
          personnage="Lady Henrietta Flusky">
        <titre>Under Capricorn</titre>
        <resume>In 1831, Irishman Charles Adare travels to Australia to start a new life with the help of his cousin who
            has just been appointed governor. When he arrives he meets powerful landowner and ex-convict Sam Flusky, who
            wants to do a business deal with him. Whilst attending a dinner party at Flusky's house, Charles meets
            Flusky's wife Henrietta who he had known as a child back in Ireland. Henrietta is an alcoholic and seems to
            be on the verge of madness.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f34" realisateur="Roberto Rossellini" date="1951" personnage="Irene Girard">
        <titre>Europa '51</titre>
        <resume/>
        <alias date="1954" pays="USA">Greatest Love, The</alias>
        <alias date="1951" pays="UK">No Greater Love</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f32" realisateur="Gianni Franciolini, Alfredo Guarini" date="1953" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Siamo donne</titre>
        <resume>Five portraits of actresses in their common life, seen as women rather than movie stars.</resume>
        <alias date="1958" pays="USA">Of Life and Love</alias>
        <alias date="1958" pays="USA">We, the Women</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f33" img="33.jpg" pdf="33.pdf" realisateur="Roberto Rossellini" date="1953"
          personnage="Katherine Joyce">
        <titre>Viaggio in Italia</titre>
        <resume>Catherine and Alexander, wealthy and sophisticated, drive to Naples to dispose of a deceased uncle's
            villa. There's a coolness in their relationship and aspects of Naples add to the strain. She remembers a
            poet who loved her and died in the war; although she didn't love him, the memory underscores romance's
            absence from her life now. She tours the museums of Naples and Pompeii, immersing herself in the Neapolitan
            fascination with the dead and noticing how many women are pregnant; he idles on Capri, flirting with women
            but drawing back from adultery. With her, he's sarcastic; with him, she's critical. They talk of divorce.
            Will this foreign couple find insight and direction in Italy?
        </resume>
        <alias date="1953" pays="France">Amour est le plus fort, L'</alias>
        <alias date="1955" pays="USA">Journey to Italy</alias>
        <alias date="1953" pays="UK">Lonely Woman, The</alias>
        <alias date="1955" pays="USA">Strangers</alias>
        <alias date="1953" pays="France">Voyage en Italie</alias>
        <alias date="1953">Voyage in Italy</alias>
        <alias date="1953">Voyage to Italy</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f30" realisateur="Roberto Rossellini" date="1954" personnage="Giovanna d'Arco (Joan of Arc)">
        <titre>Giovanna d'Arco al rogo</titre>
        <resume/>
        <alias date="1954">Joan at the Stake</alias>
        <alias date="1954">Joan of Arc at the Stake</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f31" realisateur="Roberto Rossellini" date="1954" personnage="Irene Wagner">
        <titre>Paura, La</titre>
        <resume/>
        <alias date="1954" pays="West Germany">Angst</alias>
        <alias date="1956" pays="USA">Fear</alias>
        <alias date="1955" pays="Italy">Incubo</alias>
        <alias date="1955" pays="Italy">Non credo più all'amore</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f28" img="28.jpg" pdf="28.pdf" realisateur="Anatole Litvak" date="1956" personnage="Anastasia">
        <titre>Anastasia</titre>
        <resume>Russian exiles in Paris plot to collect ten million pounds from the Bank of England by grooming a
            destitute, suicidal girl to pose as heir to the Russian throne. While Bounin is coaching her he comes to
            believe she is really Anastasia. In the end the Empress must decide her claim.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f29" img="29.jpg" pdf="29.pdf" realisateur="Jean Renoir" date="1956" personnage="Elena Sokorowska">
        <titre>Elena et les hommes</titre>
        <resume>Polnish countess Elena falls in love to a Frensh radical party's candidate, a general, in pre world war
            I Paris, but another officer pines for her.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1956">Elena and Her Men</alias>
        <alias date="1956" pays="Italy">Eliana e gli uomini</alias>
        <alias date="1956" pays="UK">Paris Does Strange Things</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f26" img="26.jpg" pdf="26.pdf" realisateur="Mark Robson" date="1958" personnage="Gladys Aylward">
        <titre>Inn of the Sixth Happiness, The</titre>
        <resume>All her life Englishwoman Gladys Aylward knew that China was the place where she belonged. Not qualified
            to be sent there as a missionary, Gladys works as a domestic to earn the money to send herself to a poor,
            remote village. There she eventually lives a full and happy life: running the inn, acting as foot inspector,
            advising the local Mandarin and even winning the heart of mixed race Captain Lin Nan. But Gladys discovers
            her real destiny when the country is invaded by Japan and the Chinese children need her to save their lives.
            Based on a true story.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f27" img="27.jpg" pdf="27.pdf" realisateur="Stanley Donen" date="1958" personnage="Anne Kalman">
        <titre>Indiscreet</titre>
        <resume>Anna Kaplan is a accomplished actress who has given up hope at finding the man of her dreams. She is in
            the middle of taking off her face cream (one of the best scenes), while talking about this subject with her
            sister, when in walks Philip Adams. She loses her concentration for a moment as she realizes that this is
            the charming, smart, and handsome man she has been waiting for. The plot thickens as they begin a love at
            first sight relationship and she finds out that he has been keeping a secret from her. When she learns of
            his lie, she becomes furious and works out a plan for revenge.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f25" realisateur="John Frankenheimer" date="1959" misc="(TV)" personnage="Governess">
        <titre>Turn of the Screw, The</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f22" realisateur="Pierre Chevalier" date="1961" misc="(uncredited)"
          personnage="Herself (cameo appearance)">
        <titre>Auguste</titre>
        <resume/>
        <alias date="1961" pays="International: English title">Kolka, My Friend</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f23" img="23.jpg" pdf="23.pdf" realisateur="Anatole Litvak" date="1961" personnage="Paula Tessier">
        <titre>Goodbye Again</titre>
        <resume>In this adaptation of Francoise Sagan's best selling novel, Paula is a beautiful, 40-year old, highly
            successful businesswoman. She is deeply in love with Roger, her mature consort of five years. Roger is a
            very charming gallant who loves Paula but is too selfish to give up his freedom to be promiscuous. When
            Paula meets Phillip, the 24-year old, immature, lawyer son of one of her rich clients, he falls hopelessly
            in love with the glamorous, sympathetic older woman and insists that the age difference will be no barrier
            to a romance. Paula resists the young man's persistent advances, but finally succumbs when Roger initiates
            yet another affair with one of his young Maisies. An affair begins, and society does not approve.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1961" pays="France">Aimez-vous Brahms?</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f24" img="24.jpg" pdf="24.pdf" realisateur="Silvio Narizzano" date="1961" misc="(TV)"
          personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Twenty-Four Hours in a Woman's Life</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f21" realisateur="Alex Segal" date="1963" misc="(TV)" personnage="Hedda Gabler">
        <titre>Hedda Gabler</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f20" realisateur="Bernhard Wicki" date="1964" personnage="Karla Zachanassian">
        <titre>Visit, The</titre>
        <resume>Carla Zachanassian had a child by Serge Miller as a teenager. When Serge refused to marry her, she was
            driven out of town. By her own wit and cunning, she has returned as a multi-millionaire for a visit. The
            town lays out the red carpet expecting big things from Carla, only to learn that her sole purpose is to see
            Serge Miller killed...
        </resume>
        <alias date="1964" pays="West Germany">Besuch, Der</alias>
        <alias date="1964" pays="France">Rancune, La</alias>
        <alias date="1964" pays="Italy">Vendetta della signora, La</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f18" img="18.jpg" pdf="18.pdf" realisateur="Saul Turell" date="1965" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Love Goddesses, The</titre>
        <resume>This insightful documentary features some of the major and most beautiful actresses to grace the silver
            screen. It shows how the movie industry changed it's depiction of sex and actresses portrayal of sex from
            the silent movie era to the present. Classic scenes are shown from the silent movie, True Heart Susie,
            starring Lillian Gish, to Love Me Tonight (1932), blending sex and sophistication, starring Jeanette
            MacDonald (pre-Nelson Eddy) and to Elizabeth Taylor in, A Place in the Sun (1951), plus much , much more.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1965">Love Goddesses: A History of Sex in the Cinema, The</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f19" img="19.jpg" pdf="19.pdf" realisateur="Anthony Asquith" date="1965" personnage="Gerda Millett">
        <titre>Yellow Rolls-Royce, The</titre>
        <resume>Three stories about the lives and loves of those who own a certain yellow Rolls-Royce:

            First purchased by the Marquess of Frinton for his wife as a belated anniversary present, the Marchiness
            finds her own use for the vehicle - one which prompts her husband to sell the car in disgust.

            Gangster Paolo Maltese's moll, Mae, thinks the Rolls is a classy car in which to tour Paolo's home town in
            Italy. When Paolo is called away to the States to finish some business, a bored Mae takes the Rolls on a
            spin through the country, enjoying both the sights and the handsome Italian photographer who crosses her
            path.

            By the outbreak of World War II, the car has come into the possession of socialite Gerda Millet. While on
            her way to visit Yugoslavian royalty, Gerda and the Rolls become (at first) unwitting and then (eventually)
            most willing participants in the Yugoslavian fight.

        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f16" img="16.jpg" pdf="16.pdf" realisateur="Ted Kotcheff" date="1967" misc="(TV)"
          personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Human Voice, The</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f17" realisateur="Hand Abramson, Hans Alfredson" date="1967" personnage="Mathilde Hartman">
        <titre>Stimulantia</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f14" realisateur="Marshall Flaum" date="1969" misc="(TV)" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Hollywood: The Selznick Years</titre>
        <resume>[Documentaire]</resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f15" img="15.jpg" pdf="15.pdf" realisateur="Gene Saks" date="1969" personnage="Stephanie Dickinson">
        <titre>Cactus Flower</titre>
        <resume>Toni Simmons believes that the only reason her married lover won't leave his wife is because of the
            children. In truth, her lover, dentist Julian Winston, doesn't have any children. In fact, Julian doesn't
            even have a wife - he just tells women he does to avoid getting involved. When Julian does decide to take
            the plunge with Toni she insists on meeting the first wife and Julian enlists the aid of his long-time
            nurse/receptionist Stephanie Dickinson to play the part.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f12" realisateur="Roberto Guerra, Elia Hershon" date="1970" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Henri Langlois</titre>
        <resume>Documentary about French (Turkish born) film historian Henri Langlois (1914-1977), co-founder of the
            Cinemathèque Française, which progressed from just 10 films in 1936 to 60,000 films in the early 70s. The
            film also deals with the manifestations of support for Langlois following 1968 French Minister of Culture
            André Malraux's failed attempt to replace him as head of the Cinemathèque.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1970">Langlois</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f13" img="13.jpg" pdf="13.pdf" realisateur="Guy Green" date="1970" personnage="Libby Meredith">
        <titre>Walk in the Spring Rain</titre>
        <resume>The Merediths move to an isolated farm. Mrs. Meredith and the neighbour Will Cade become friends and
            eventually lovers.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f11" img="11.jpg" pdf="11.pdf" realisateur="Fielder Cook" date="1973" personnage="Mrs. Frankweiler">
        <titre>From the Mixed-Up Files of Mrs. Basil E. Frankweiler</titre>
        <resume>Precocious Claudia and her brother run away from home and hide in the Metropolitan Museum in New York.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1973" pays="UK">Hideaways, The</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f10" img="10.jpg" pdf="10.pdf" realisateur="Sidney Lumet" date="1974" personnage="Greta">
        <titre>Murder on the Orient Express</titre>
        <resume>After solving a case, Hercule Poirot takes the Orient Express home. On board is Ratchett, a millionaire
            and his secretary Hector MacQueen and butler Beddoes. Also there is a Count and Countess, a Colonel, a bossy
            American woman, an Italian, a Princess and her nurse and Pierre, the conductor. The train gets stuck in the
            snow and during the night, Ratchett is murdered, stabbed many times. Poirot and Bianchi (the train's
            detective and friend) investigate and discover that Ratchett and the rest of the passengers are involved in
            the Daisy Armstrong case in which a child was taken for ransom and then horribly killed...
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f9" realisateur="?" date="1975" misc="(TV)" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Salute to Orson Welles, A</titre>
        <resume>[Documentaire]</resume>
        <alias date="1975" pays="TV">3rd American Film Institute Life Achievement Award: A Salute to Orson Welles
        </alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f8" img="08.jpg" pdf="08.pdf" realisateur="Vincente Minnelli" date="1976"
          personnage="Countess Sanziani">
        <titre>Matter of Time, A</titre>
        <resume/>
        <alias date="1976" pays="Italy">Nina</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f7" img="07.gif" pdf="07.pdf" realisateur="Ingmar Bergman" date="1978" personnage="Charlotte">
        <titre>Höstsonaten</titre>
        <resume>After having neglected her children for many years, world famous pianist Charlotte visits her daughter
            Eva in her home. To her surprise she finds her other daughter, Helena, there as well. Helena is mentally
            impaired, and Eva has taken Helena out of the institution where their mother had placed her. The tension
            between Charlotte and Eva only builds up slowly, until a nightly conversation releases all the things they
            have wanted to tell each other.
        </resume>
        <alias date="1978" pays="USA">Autumn Sonata</alias>
        <alias date="1978" pays="West Germany">Herbstsonate</alias>
        <alias date="1978" pays="France">Sonate d'automne</alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f6" realisateur="Marty Pasetta" date="1979" misc="(TV)" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Salute to Alfred Hitchcock, A</titre>
        <resume>[Documentaire]</resume>
        <alias date="1979" pays="TV">7th American Film Institute Life Achievement Award: A Salute to Alfred Hitchcock,
            The
        </alias>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f5" img="05.jpg" pdf="05.pdf" realisateur="Alan Gibson" date="1982" misc="(TV)"
          personnage="Golda Meir">
        <titre>Woman Called Golda, A</titre>
        <resume/>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f4" realisateur="Gene Feldman" date="1985" misc="(archive footage)" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Ingrid</titre>
        <resume>[Documentaire]</resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f3" img="03.jpg" pdf="03.pdf" realisateur="Steven Martin" date="1993" misc="(uncredited)"
          personnage="Actress in 'Spellbound' Clip">
        <titre>Theremin: An Electronic Odyssey</titre>
        <resume>A documentary about the amazing life of Leon Theremin, inventor of the theremin, the electronic musical
            instrument so beloved of 50s sci-fi movie music. Theremin amazed America with his instrument until his
            kidnapping by Soviet agents in the mid-30s. Upon his release from a labor camp, he worked on surveillance
            devices for the KGB. Almost 60 years later, he is brought back to America for a touching reunion with his
            friends and colleagues.
        </resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f2" realisateur="Chuck Workman" date="1995" misc="(TV)" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>First 100 Years: A Celebration of American Movies, The</titre>
        <resume>[Documentaire]</resume>
    </film>
    <film filmref="f1" realisateur="Vassili Silovic" date="1996" misc="(archive footage)" personnage="Herself">
        <titre>Orson Welles: The One-Man Band</titre>
        <resume>[Documentaire]</resume>
        <alias date="1996" pays="UK: TV title">Lost Films of Orson Welles, The</alias>
    </film>
</filmographie>
